all right welcome to our first official
one because the last one didn't exist in
Syria since we erased it last time we
talked about this right what we were
gonna do this week um between last week
and this week and I don't give homework
but I did give homework which was what
if there is a meta issue to solve if
there are sectors that we can break into
and start talking about out with three
people but you know and there's more
people what are those what do those
sectors look like so I sat with that and
I also talked to my child the other
person I would have to figure out
community with because she's the one who
would be moving there with me
what would be her ideal community what
would be my ideal community and and we
be not together neither of us is gonna
get everything we want in fact even it
just being and BC is gonna be hard
enough but that is it's part of going
through this process how is the last
week been for you two have you guys sat
without or did you do something
different um yeah um I was thinking
about it and talking about it with my
mom who recently also joins gang be
communities she's over here right now no
and yeah I like talking about what we
would like what would be the best type
of community that if we were to join
what like at this moment and what would
be the best type if we were to join it
like in the future like year a couple
years are probably like when my children
were grown up so probably like five
years six years down the road like how
that would look like
you can mentioned your child so yeah we
were talking about how would it be with
kids and what would it be without kids
because that does kind of affect the
type of community that you might live in
or the type of space you would need like
our thing is it's you know we'd be like
six people we're like we're like the you
know some
communities only have six people in them
and it's like we're an entire community
moving into a new community that's like
a lot of space needed so and as opposed
to only like three people you know to
move into one so so a lot of that stuff
and what type of like projects like that
we would enjoy within the community like
things that we enjoy and have skills in
that we could come together with other
people and do with them yeah in my case
it was just the intensive week because
here in our we call it home unit in
Spain we have a gallery and we had an
exhibition and it was the first official
cultural event in our house after this
lockdown in Spain so I'm a little bit
charged with his impressions of how the
new normal is in the field of art and
creativity and I done I have done my
homework so I was thinking a little bit
about this topic what leads finally to
to community what what we can explore
discover discuss and I put out some
words in an hour block this was my last
week thank you I don't know exactly
where to go from here
but what I would like to be able to do
is talk about the different sectors like
what that would look like to break it
down because I know I broke it down
based on like my needs and wants right
that well we need shelter so that either
means I have to physically own a place
or I need to rent from someone who
physically owns one a pre-existing
community and looking at it from from
that stance there's going to be some
communities that of course need to solve
plumbing and some
which don't need to solve plumbing
because they're on the plumbing grid
right there they're part of the city and
they have to follow all of those and if
there are a hundred people communities
which is just the number in my head it's
not necessarily it's a sticking point
but of those hundred like how many would
need to be on the legal team because of
the legal team to me is the one that
isn't as what is the word like I do the
legal work in British Columbia it's not
going to be transferable to the legal
work in Tennessee right transferable to
legal work in New Zealand but water
this is although under the legal
department it's not the same water is
the same the world over
so there might be well am I getting a
fresh source of water am i getting salt
water but it's not good at you know I
mean like that's gonna be more broad
throughout the project so um yeah what
do people think about I don't even know
what that necessarily looks like but
that is what i sat with is just going
through the different different sectors
that that would be needed to start a
community um I don't know if anyone else
did that though to be able to compare
them right till to say well is this but
if we start there
it could be something that um breaks
down more naturally right there's we all
need to eat in order to be able to eat
you need water in order to be able you
know you need to know what what foods to
plant in what yeah for my site I went
through this process of founding a
community so I can remember some
ingrediences I would say you need a kind
of recipe something which is more or
less common sense to together with other
people this is mostly some ideas about
permaculture health for business or
economy or political issues or whatever
and the other thing is that it is a very
complex situation so you need a mix of
space time independence of the people
and in some cases also minimal of
capital to do it I would say the most
important thing is that everybody who is
really interested to join this process
of starting a community should be aware
about what she or he really want because
there are a lot of illusions and a lot
of imaginations about what could be done
how beautiful it could be so for a lot
of people even after this time now after
this lockdown in Europe and elsewhere we
have a lot of requests from people and
there are full of illusions and they use
this idea of community clan as a
projection you know it's it's a
beautiful screen to put all on it what
you would like to have and what you
actually miss and this you have to sort
out and in the beginning a little bit
yes and that is like how do we go
through that process in a more meta way
because the two things super real to
start a community if it doesn't already
exist if it does exist which one work
makes your which one meets your needs
which one wants you there right it's
like a matchmaking but if it doesn't
already exist then you need to find
people and a place right you need to
find the lens of whether it's leased or
owned or you have access to it and you
need to be able to have a group of
people whether that's three people or
whether and that is a big for me I don't
want a community with three people
otherwise if you home study by myself I
want a 50 to 100
Persson community because I know what
the what that means for labor right that
over sharing and if we're growing food
for sharing in that and and I really
want our food to be intertwined I don't
like that's a big part of why I'm moving
to Canada and why I want to move to
community is so that I can eat better
without needing to put in the labor both
mental and physical that we can share in
that and so I loved I briefly looked
through your article that you wrote one
and I loved the idea of the the rules
that aren't quite like that are much
more flexible right like lower your
expectations but also to know what your
true sticking points are to know what is
it like I also one of the big cabby
one of the reasons I want to move to
community is because of the pandemic is
because I want to be able to have a
insulated community where we don't have
to socially isolate but we can socially
isolate from the rest of the world if
needed right and having a protocol for
coming in and going out that's something
that I would want in place right we
don't want to wait till there's a
community in place and then figure that
out because they've we're gonna have
very different views people who don't
think there's any issue and want to be
able to come and go as they please and
people think there is an issue and they
want to be able to instantly to make
themselves safe those are very different
sticking points so I was wondering what
your advice is on that that like being
open to this much and having as little
expectations is a great way to conform a
community but also to know what it is
you want in it one or two things so that
you can design a world around it or your
life around it yeah I can answer
directly but I don't know if I want to
join questions or X something or
whatever yeah me and my mom read your
article and we really liked it we also
like the simple rules like how you made
the effort to make it make them as
simple and follow able like as
we'll and have people be responsible for
themselves you know policing yourself
being independent of yourself you know
to make it work
you know because you want to be there so
you're going to be flexible and and and
make it work with the people there
because there's reasons that you want to
continue living there and I guess kind
of something that is like an example of
a community but not I guess an example
of is where I work so I work at a
residential facility which has ten
people living there but then you have 50
staff who come and go and we are on like
three different shifts so and so this
has been since March we've been like on
lockdown and so you have all the the
people you go home to your regular house
and what you believe if you believe it's
real or if you believe it's not real
really doesn't matter because when you
come to your shared space you just
practice courteousness by making sure
you wash your hands before you touch
anything that's shared by other people
if you uh you know coughing like if you
cough or sneeze you make sure you cover
your your mouth and even though we share
like all the same bathrooms and we eat
together and everything that because
it's a residential facility so we're
we're doing a lot of sharing of air so
we just police ourselves and we just use
like the I guess like common hygiene
courtesy and out of 50 people no one has
gotten sick at all there and so we just
you know it's so the power
behind what everyone specifically
believes really didn't matter because
when we came together in our shared
spaces we just respect each other you
know anyway like by by just and just
taking that responsibility on ourselves
and we know that you know we have our
bosses above us who encourage us but
even if we didn't have them like you
know we were washing our hands before we
were touching everyone's food anyway but
just so like that so I guess what I was
with me and my mom were discussing was
when we were we're supposed to move out
of our house that we live in now to a
bigger house next year and so we were
thinking about having because there's so
many of us we do need our own like unit
to live in so I know some communities
they have people living in like a large
shared house we're just like in their
own rooms and others have people living
in their own individual homes and I I
think that that might be an easier way
to have people still maintain their own
thing when they're it because when
they're in their own private home but
then when when everyone comes together
into their community time and their
community projects together then you
just have that you know you're you're
behaving appropriately because you're
you know belief in yourself to be
flexible and kind to those in the
community you know because you like
being there so I think a lot of the
conflict in community comes up that we
do not have the same ideas on what those
common things are and the fact the more
we put it on the common to figure out
what that is the more conflict there is
because it's what do you mean you're not
washing your hands that wasn't already
what you were doing right so it's like
common sense but I can tell you as a 40
year old that's just like I know it well
theoretically it was life or death it's
maybe less life or death
to touch my face to constantly be
touching my face I know I'm not supposed
to be and I can't not so and I can't
wash my hands enough to keep up with it
so like there's the level of which of
when I wish I could do and I even agree
that that is the level that should be
accommodated and yet I can't accommodate
it so and my kid I'm like oh god what's
gonna happen when she goes back to
school all these other kids have this
level of Hygiene of like yeah we all
wash your hands every five minutes so my
kid doesn't yet still no better point
because I'm more insulated us rather
than having her constantly on public
touching things to anyway so yeah I'm
interesting from you one what when
you're having those like what I stated
that there is a beauty in having as few
rules as possible and yet there are if
you know what your sticking points are
to make sure that that is actually in
place and yet like if I rewrote my whole
life for this pandemic right it's not
this time to make I'm rewriting it for
its pandemics in general right it's like
oh how do you insulate as a tiny
community versus being in a big city
where it's nearly impossible but it
won't be in place for the next
catastrophe right whatever the next one
is it's coming down the line isn't going
to have my viewpoint on how we should
act in this so no matter how stringent
you are you need to be able to
understand that you have to come
together and change and evolve and yet
at the same time I don't want to leave
it up to chance whether or not we're
intermingling our food because I want
our food to be intermingled right I want
at least our our big meal of the day to
be eaten together and it's even
breakfast and lunch to be able to to
work together to share in that labor and
time so I don't have to do it for my kid
and there's more you know anyway your
urine stats on what you would suggest
for like having roles in the beginning
versus being flexible and what that okay
as you know our community is a little
bit special so I try to reduce it a
little bit the answer and I catch you
your idea of where and how you could
figure out a starting point and I catch
the other idea about health and and
respect for others I'm sitting here in a
700 year old house in Spain it was a
ruin and over 20 years it was rebuilded
by more than 150 people from all over
the world so to gather these people to
form teams and groups to rebuild this
house we had a kind of speed-dating so
we have this experience of trying to
form a group a team where you have only
very few time to figure out if you want
to spend the next three or four weeks in
a very condensed social situation with
other people so my question to discuss
we figured out to make a kind of party
we invited the people we shot them some
pictures and then we we had some talks
with everybody kind of interviewed and
then we decided who would be part of the
next working session and my question was
imagine at 3:00 in the night you go to
the toilet and the other one is leaving
this toilet are you okay with this if
you okay with this and you know this
after some seconds with a person it's
it's it's embedded in our human mankind
to have a very good taste of what is the
maximum which is possible with somebody
if you can answer yes really clear yes
then this can be somebody to start
something and I'm sure nobody knows in
the moment
of starting any kind of community what
it really means to start this because
you don't know the next catastrophe you
don't know the next event on my travel
through communities in Europe I ask the
the community members when it goes wrong
why it goes wrong and the question was
ever the same the question was the
answer was love or money so these are
the two topics you have to be aware of
when people think in the beginning it is
a good idea to do something together and
later on the way it becomes stressful
then it was all the time one of these
two and in our community now after five
years officially community and after 15
years of living with these people
together it is just this it's not more
nothing else and so under love is that
all children children family personal
relations between members or between
members and people outside of the
community this is something you can call
it a game changer and you have to be
aware about this the other thing is see
a community more like swarm of bees in a
beehive it is nothing stable where you
imagine to find 10 20 or 100 people you
start something you are much more or
less in the same age and and you will
spend the rest of your life with these
people in a way this all the time coming
and going
like in the Beehive no one bee has a
lifespan of 54 days something like this
so there's a lot of change all the time
also changing it's something which is
quite normal
yes thank you
and so that was well Linda was talking I
had I was writing down like the metrics
of finding the community that already
exists and it's even the idea of having
your private space versus common space
breaking that down into what does it
mean right I number one want my own
bedroom I don't want to sleep with other
unless it's maybe my child I don't want
to sleep with other people at night in
my room right I might be a little more
okay sharing a bathroom but even then
I'm not really okay with it
whereas a kitchen I'm more okay with
anyway like like having it actually be
broken down into if I'm coming into this
community is there space for six people
right is there a house that has X number
of bedrooms available like actually
breaking it down because I know there
are these things already exist thirty is
the intentional community websites but
they don't break it down in a way that's
actually like usable to find it because
they're not they're not trying to make
it more easy for the person coming into
the community to find community and if
they aren't why are they in existence I
don't quite understand why they have a
meta community if they're not helping
people find which community is the most
important for them but they've picked
like they can't necessarily have dozens
of criteria right so and you would know
very fast if you have dozens of criteria
you're not gonna find a community that
works for you but if you have the more
criteria you put in the less and less
community is there will be this this
house the Venn diagram of those
interconnecting ones right like I want
there has to be children in fact there
has to be a girl around the age of seven
seven eight six seven eight there needs
to be in order for me to move there I
can't look that up right
immunity pieces and it's like well why
would you be that rigid well I have a
six or seven year old right who needs to
have that that connection like a lot of
this is solved with a database but at
the same time then it's like okay so now
that I know there aren't communities
that exist how do you create one from
scratch how do you create one that is
and having one tool that can help people
do that is I guess when I'm wanting but
also I know that the more I focus on
technology the less I do it with the
people that are here the less effective
it is because there aren't I don't have
hundreds of people to create technology
with and therefore it has to be from the
people that are present something that
is offered from day one right that there
is a benefit to coming together and
discussing community a benefit to coming
together and figuring out our army it's
getting that right are we getting closer
to our visions of community and what
does that look like and I don't know
what this could look like so that we're
constantly bringing in new people
because I you would send something
earlier one about people knowing what
they need in community and I think
having something like a Pinterest board
something that is like here's my idea
like me and my kids ideal version of a
community right like the unicorn of
exactly what I want there to be in
knowing I know I get any of that let
alone all of that right I might get one
or two things my two or three absolute
needs and then as much of my wants as is
possible in the community creating that
together it would be very powerful
anyway I'm rambling on to come together
and talk about what it is that we want
in community and then a way towards it
that could be done whether there's four
people or hundreds of people I don't
necessarily say I think for most of the
people it's easier to join an existing
project this leads to two options
you can start one the advantage is that
you can define what you want and you
have the power to invite people you want
to have where you believe that you find
really what what you were looking for in
your community so you are talking here
with the founder so I feel really
comfortable in my community because I'm
co-founder and I could participate in
the design of this community the
disadvantage is that you will start if
you try to grow in an organic way you
will start from a little group I would
say in our case it was four people and
we were knowing each other for years so
this is something like a point of
crystallization and you are like like a
little light in the darkness for other
people so I I have only the experience
of founding it finally after looking
some other communities because people
have a kind of list a checklist and they
ask questions and then they calculate
could be could not be so in my case
didn't hit really with my profession and
my intention to live in different
countries and to move sometimes for my
projects and so finally we founded this
community but yeah you you have to jump
in this cold water and you have to
to use technology like like this to
gather people you have to invite a lot
of people and then you will see this
this is what normally happen a little
group maybe four maybe five maybe six
people in this little group it's also
easier to to set up this is basic rule
set that you can invite others and it's
easier to explain what it is to be part
of your community later on and I think
that is the difference between creating
a community and creating the meta
community is that if I'm looking to
start a community I want the people who
are actually physically gonna be living
in that community and we want to work
through all of that process together and
people will come attracted to it and or
fall away based on what we're coming up
with but that process is very arduous
how how do people who are out there know
that you exist how you do compared to
someone else how you before can and come
back together and so having a more meta
community to say this isn't like the
chance is that the three of us are ever
gonna live together in near zero right
we're in very different geographical
locations now we could write if we were
like dedicated to it yes find a place
that works for all of us and that is
like okay it's hard enough to find a
community that works even if you are all
in BC and looking for one in BC let
alone now we open it up to the world
right and look for that so figuring out
from the meta side like what if we're
getting together and talking about what
it is we want in a community what what
our Pinterest beautiful perfect
community is that we're never getting as
well as you know my bare minimum then I
need idea to be BC with my kid French
from England food coming from this spot
of the most communities break up over
love and money
to me feel
like okay what is the money piece needs
to be there so what does it look like
you know if you're coming into one what
are you putting in what are you getting
that is one of the things I really liked
about your article was a clear
definition of when you're part of when
you join the community versus when you
exit the community right having that be
more established what is the buy-in what
is the is there buy-in are you putting
committee into 30 hours a week or you
can need 30 hours a month like what is
the actual because that also more weeds
out I don't even know what I'm talking
about here yes I see it weeds out like
if you don't even if I only want to do
ten hours of work a week other people
like no we're gonna be doing 80 hours
work we are gonna be that it weeds out
our differences around this right I
don't know what that looks like for love
versus for money besides the very
obvious how open are we need two
different kinds of families and
different kinds of relationships within
the community and then how do we define
that right how much autonomy is there in
the family unit how much do we decide
how you raise your kids versus you
decide how you raise your kids and
that's easier said than done except when
you come up to community and you're like
oh no I didn't want my kid constantly
surrounded by other kids that are doing
X or Y how much is ya how much maybe
that's more the meta community is
figuring out how do we break into
communities to start those conversations
and how much work can we do together
before breaking into those groups right
not here are the people I'm creating a
BC community with but here are the
people who were discussing what it takes
to create a community at all and I might
be on the legal department or I might be
on the plumbing or and I'd be on the
food department it's going to be
collecting that information and bringing
it together right so that not each
individual project has to figure that
out
uniquely how do you when someone comes
in how do they find a project that works
for them how can we solve the people
problem would be a big meta problem to
solve
people come in which project is the best
for them where is their area of expert
and doing it that way and again I'm
rambling I apologize one thing like me
and my mom were discussing because we're
moving and because it's extremely
expensive we live in San Diego
California and even when you have a
college degree and working your fields
and our supervisor at your job you still
only make $40,000 a year and the average
house costs $500,000 so you're kind of
like screwed yo but what they have here
are a lot of manufactured house
communities which are like sell for like
really cheap because they only
depreciate in value so you have people
living there because you know it was the
home they afford to live in and they
live there and then if they move out
they have to sell their manufactured
house for like $15,000 sometimes so we
were thinking that we're gonna move
there and so that is in a way a
community no the people are already
there and there isn't really a specific
set of rules like there are rules but
not too rigid people are allowed to be
like there do their own thing in their
own house and so what we were thinking
was wherever we move to we wouldn't be
afraid to get to know our neighbors cuz
coming from where we moved from was a
city where it was scary it was a real
crime city in central New York bait so
there it got scary to know some of your
neighbors but here now we've lived here
for three years so we've gotten over
some of the
the people PTSD and realize that maybe
we should get to know our neighbors and
do something there that can create
community out of the people that are
there you know like start a garden and
then the person on both sides of us are
right there say hey I I made this dirt
right here and I put this stuff in it
and you're welcome to put put plants in
it and and take plants from it you know
like how people do like the the free
library but do it with something and you
know that's something easy like seeds
and plants or we're really my mom are
artistic so if we just go outside and
start doing stuff you know where we
might find neighbors who are in the mood
to be a community and maybe it'll work
so that's like we're at with so we had
thought about the idea of how do you
start one when you can't find when there
isn't one existing really like how do
you start with where you are you know so
that's gonna be a little experiment I
love it because it's the easiest way to
create a community is to create one from
what already exists like truly just
connect with your neighbors and figure
it out and yet it's the least attractive
to me like I'm like I wouldn't know my
neighbors I'm like I don't want any of
my neighbor burgers and why why is that
right like part of it is that we're not
in it intentionally right so there is a
Eco part of it like I have to kind of
put that on on the table and be like hey
who wants to do this and then getting no
one wanting to do it is already hard it
anyway but yeah I like that from my best
day yeah okay
in our situation because of the whole
planned ma thing we don't have any idea
what the housing situation is going to
look like it in Southern California when
this is over we don't even know where we
can move to or what we can afford or who
we're going to find around us so I'm
right now not even picturing that it's
going to be rural or urban I mean we
might be forced into a housing situation
so I feel like it's hard for us to have
a good day dream right now because of
yeah and sort of stuck right there you
know it's also like for me there's
something hybrid coming up between the
two of like oh if I didn't have to start
from scratch
right I didn't have to find land and
create everything from zero and or work
on land or two here like Vancouver
cohousing did that was highly expensive
so they're not being gonna be able to
sell it for any less than you know
market right
I know there are towns they're
struggling finding you know ten to
twelve people ten to twelve families who
are willing to move to somewhere in BC
right like okay anywhere that's a BC
that has internet this this and that and
then you know there's there's other
implications involved in moving to a
small town and say hey but something
like a trailer park where instead of you
moving in and saying okay what we're
gonna change the entire culture here
whether it's wanted or not is okay well
there's me and three other families and
we're all gonna find a place a trailer
park that we're all in and we at least
know these four families want some kind
of intentional community and then it's
more open then you start a garden you
can see people working in it and also
inviting the other people and inviting
them on their terms right but it's not I
don't know there's something there
that's very they're very powerful and my
phone's ringing then you know I I would
say if you move to a to a city for any
reason you switch your your home base
what you try normally to find people
you try to identify people people with
same needs like your mother with a kid
you go to a kindergarten there is a
blackboard you put something on this
board and say I'm new in town let's make
a party I want to do something so you
you give a reason to meet and I think
this is a kind of starting point for
finding people for whatever reason so I
know from communities in Europe that
sometimes somebody is like like a scout
and he found an old fat he found some
houses a big mansion old castle or
whatever or here in Spain we have
abandoned villages you can have for one
euro it's a little bit more than one
dollar you can have one village if you
want you just have to make a good
project and present this project to the
town mayor of the neighbor village and
you can get this ha this this whole
village if you have an idea what you
want to do but however I would say the
first step is to find the people if you
find somebody you feel really good with
this person then you will manage all
other difficulties on the way so from my
perspective the most important is a
human so so I'm looking for the the
person and then I ask what you want to
do and I tell what I want to do and then
we try to find where we can walk
side-by-side so this would be my
starting point if I would move to
California
to make a party
yeah I like the idea it's not
metacommunity but yet it is unified like
local people who wants to start a
community it's not really what I want to
do because I don't want to go through
that whole process again from scratch
should have to reinvent everything but
at the same time if that is instead what
am I trying to say if instead of me
going off and doing that
there is still emetic components of ok
let's have this be our meeting 9:00 a.m.
on Mondays hi I just bought a zoom
account that I'm figuring out how to how
to get into it like I can bring people
to that and when we break off into
groups there's the BC group right that's
broken off in this part that's broken
off so it's still bringing the people to
a medic conversation but also honoring
that this is also probably going to
split along geographical lines right and
having it I'm more likely to move to
Alberta or Ontario than I am to moved to
the States
I'm more likely to move to Europe that I
am too moved to the States like there's
someone offered me the perfect place in
Europe and was like your needs are taken
care of I would figure it out but my
money is reliant on maybe an NBC so hmm
my so it's Europe it's totally different
with house prices and the needs for
normal life
especially in rural areas so money is
not really the question it's more the
question of confident self confidence of
ideas what to do so don't charge a
community that they deliver any sense
for your life if you have this already
in in your suitcase when you arrive and
then it's ok
[Music]
I don't know where to start
don't know where to start to find and
for my specific means right wanting to
find people in BC who like I don't even
know how to like put that out there
people who just want their community BFM
BC therefore if you want to call housing
in in DC my first question would be are
there any houses which are available
affordable and can I identify the owner
behind this this mentioned this this
houses this would be the first question
and if you find this person you find
somebody even if this person want to
sell this property you find somebody who
is already on your site because he don't
want to live there but he he would he
would help you to find a solution
because he like to sell it
so maybe he's embedded in some
associations or he knew people because
he has four years with family background
this these houses so this would be a
starting point on one side I think on
the other side such a little dream of
some nice pictures kind of portfolio
what it could be if you would find 20 or
30 people to start the project a little
bit text maybe some videos then you have
a crystallization point and you can make
a party just for party this would be my
starting point if I would like to follow
this
but you yeah unfortunately with where I
am that is less doable just because no
there's no property that's cheap enough
like even in Vancouver where collective
houses is becoming more and more common
there's no place you can find for under
like seven hundred eight hundred dollars
per room times the amount because it's
like if there's a room if there's a
space that's four or five bedrooms it's
going to get turned into a collective
post and so of course it brings up
supply and demand and even the further
out of the city you go there's basically
nowhere that is cheap NB c-- except for
i think small towns that are trying to
revitalize and so looking for people who
are open to moving anywhere in BC and
setting that criterion possibly also
figuring out like although it's on my
list of perfect like um more ideal
community starting a tech a technology
company where that is your finance is
instead of it being a bakery or a farm
yes I want that to exist on the property
but the number one way we make our bills
suit technology because it's a tip like
that's where my mind goes that's where I
can put stuff in where I can contribute
and it's also a way to but how to
explain that so that I'm gonna attract
people is a whole leather there's a
whole other problem for everything that
I do I don't know how many times you you
bought or sold property so don't think
too much about the official price of
something here in in Europe even before
this lockdown we had a lot of times this
situation that there was a really a kind
of fantasy price for for something and
finally it was sold for twenty thirty
forty percent it's a little bit hidden
but not not so in in the public view but
this official prices are just what
somebody want
and not he get he will get finally so
you can offer whatever you want and
sometimes it happens in the way you like
it
so this is one thing don't don't see
this as given and without any any option
to change this would be in general way
of talking and thinking about this the
other thing is I imagine that in in the
political sector we will see a lot of
advertising a lot of research about new
options to reanimate life in cities
because after this lockdown you have a
lot of abandoned buildings offices they
are not in use anymore
there will be no employee returning to
this building and you have a lot of fear
in in the departments in the cities what
will happen with all these houses big
houses even big houses so I would expect
that you find very open open people in
in the political sector in some cities
to discuss with them you have an idea of
cohousing you would like to to try this
with the power of marketing and
communication skills of a town so this
is another idea to to contact people in
in a way which is not possible for one
person even with a nice YouTube channel
so this would be another idea too to
find China
where you can expect a lot of possible
[Music]
people interested in what you want to
deliver finally focused on the meta like
if I have to do all of this work one I
can't but would be all not even if I
could and I did all this work I don't
want the next person to have to do it
the next person have to do it but maybe
that's not my problems to solve it until
it it's naturally the problem that needs
to get solved like if I'm the only one
who finds that a problem then it's not a
problem to solve but if enough of us are
getting together and realize they might
20 of us get together we realize we need
to fork because we don't have the same
vision it's like wait how do we hold the
nut make us stay together but like fork
in a way that like still uses the
information and the energy we've put in
but then how can we create that for
other people which might be the natural
way for it to happen
hmm I know I know one thing that
happened to me when when it was an
amazing experience to realize the
bigness of the world like the city I was
born in I lived there for 30 years in
the I didn't even move out of the really
the the main neighborhood that would
that psycho town that we lived on and
then to move 3,000 miles away it just
made me realize for the first time that
the world is actually has places that
you can go in it okay you know even
though you know it like I know Europe
exists but you know ten years ago I
would feel inside that it would be it's
too far I can't do it I can't get there
it's too many problems but then actually
when you do step off into you know on
really and make a chance and do
something then you you realize that
really almost anything is it's
attainable you know and so no I do have
conversations like about well if I can't
you know that other countries exist in
other countries are also an option you
know so I just try not to limit limit
myself to this is what I want but I can
only find it here because the world is
full of so many different places and and
you can actually get there you know
that's a thing so I don't want to
advertise special companies but you have
a lot of options to spend some months in
communities traveling with very few
money in Europe and help inside of
communities and a lot of American
visitors even are coming to our project
over the year so so I think this is not
a big deal it is just to find to find a
platform where you can pre-select some
places and if you are focused on
communities you can select in this way
and and you can set up a strategy to to
meet maybe six or seven in in in a month
or in two months and if you feel that
having a kid is a kind of handicap in in
this case it is not because you will
write nails and make calls to these
communities and if they see any problem
you are
sure I don't need to go to this place so
you will pre-select in a very organic
way and you will end up in communities
which are happy to to see some kids
around and even kids from other
countries so there's a bigger barrier to
me than my kid cuz I agree that like
anyone who has kids in their community
knows that a new kid is gonna have a
benefit to those anyway it's gonna be is
my disability is that I can't actually
contribute even in my ideal health I can
probably only contribute like four hours
a day five days a week and that would be
when I'm healthier than I am now
and so therefore that would be 20 hours
a week I don't know whether any group
would accept someone coming especially
someone with a kid right so those two
things together but if that's just a
barrier in my head and there's actually
communities that would then so okay
last in the last session we talked a
little bit about expectation so if you
would contact the community with any
expectation of any timetable you could
help as a mother with the kid coming for
a visit of two weeks or whatever skip
this community it's unrealistic if you
come you will automatically try to do
your best and give your best and nobody
serious would would count any hours for
this so it's my own story I could still
do it you open up a whole new
possibility one coming your up going
traveling around pick you oh my god
that's a whole other possibility but ah
what I really want to do now is find
another single mom who wants to go on
that journey together or a single parent
who wants to go on that journey together
to like mad shall be like let's find one
that Oats on both of us with two kids
because I can't do the executive
functioning by myself but yeah that's
maybe I direct I had to
a little bit something inside of you but
even I like to push this in the
conversation because I gave a lot of
answers but I also would like to have an
answer from both of you we are contacted
in the time of the lockdown before also
but now more than before nearly every
day by single mothers with kids and one
of the first questions on this list is
how many kids are in the space in your
space and actually there are no kids
here in Spain so there must be somebody
with a lot of trust and power and and
energy to say okay I am the first so
my reply to this question to all these
single mothers is yeah somebody need to
be the first I have this talk seven
times a week I explain every everything
in an honest way what what you can
expect if you come but somebody need to
be the first one otherwise it doesn't
work so my question to both of you is
you can identify very easily a lot of
single mothers with kids the question
from the perspective of a man is why you
can't come together what is so
complicated if we want to hunt an animal
it's very easy for a man to find other
and and to build a team if we are clear
about the target if we feel the same
needs and and for sure both of you are
seeing a lot of times it would be good
to have the other one for some hours in
the day so why it doesn't happen
I think a lot like intentional community
it comes down to love and money it's
like well I mean I have a room that I'm
responsible in finding someone who is
compatible with me to live in it even
though I don't rent out myself my dad
looks hit currently where I was I was
like constantly and now it's one bedroom
than a bathroom so it's not two bedrooms
because I'm constantly looking for
another single parent heycome it's
harder enough to like imagine sharing
your space and then you have to go
through or what are our parenting styles
right you're basically asking two people
to co-parent without having the love and
affection for one another and or
bringing you bring all of your make it
into it and it's the biggest love and
money right it's like all right
now you can kind of take money out of it
and be like okay how much are we putting
in how much do you do you function but I
would say even though everything I just
said the biggest barrier is also not
thinking it's a possibility not know you
know what I mean like where do I go to
find this other mother where do I go to
find this other person besides just
putting an ad on Craigslist and so then
I get whoever just responds which is I'm
okay with because I can weed out who
doesn't work but um that's scary
right like if there isn't a way to
necessarily put it out there and be like
my ideal is someone else with a daughter
who's around seven or eight that is my
ideal so but if anyway if I find
something super compatible with me but
our kids aren't compatible that's not
going to work our kids have to be
compatible and we have to be compatible
in order for us to theoretically be
living together or in the same community
together
I don't know I mean I can see yeah I
mean I agree would you believe that
those are reasons but I guess I would I
don't really know why I mean if there
was I only think about I wouldn't want
to necessarily because I have three so I
wouldn't want to move which three you
know somewhere so I can think of women
with like multiple kids to uproot them
from wherever they were from and moved
somewhere but if I was to do it like I
would do it like locally like I wouldn't
mind being the first person if my kids
could continue so I go to the same
schools and stuff like that to be to be
the first person living with kids in a
community of people with no kids so if
it was locally I wouldn't really mind
that you know cuz kids they're easy kids
is easier for kids to get along I think
than adults to get along cause they're
more flexible because they're still
learning and growing you know but that's
always put off any sort of traveling
until I at least have two of them grown
up it's only got to bring one around but
um
yeah I'm not sure oh yeah it probably if
um the mother had someone like a
relative or someone even if they didn't
have necessarily but if they were a
single parent and not a two-parent to
make the jump into moving being the
first family being the first person with
the child in a community with people
without kids they probably would just
want like a teammate with them so maybe
if you have someone in your community
that is kind of a nurturing type person
earner recurring type personality that
would be open to being like the the tour
guide or trying to make a connection
like if you get a mother that will come
they're like interested in moving in so
probably the first person or they should
get like linked up specifically with
like whoever would be really just
someone who would make them feel more
calm the most comfortable about having
their kid there so under they felt like
they could I don't know go to glad this
yeah type my mother type figure if they
were the first person with a kid there I
don't know maybe maybe someone who has
adult kids you know or I don't know some
sort of connection they have to have
have a connection with someone that
already is there I think yeah Linda is
on to something
about operating your kid's life to go to
something
uploading your kid's life to be the
first one is very it's a lot it's what
to do you don't know whether you're
gonna be compatible the community
whether your kid's gonna be compatible
with the community but if there is a way
to match them before they ever get there
were they're like hey my kid is six if
there was another and whether gender
matters or not I know it matters to my
kid so if there was another kid in this
range that would be great so finding
those pairs but bigger than that it's if
I know I can be somewhere for two weeks
to see if we're compatible I can do that
for to like I'm okay with my kid not
having a friend for two weeks especially
if there's you know other adults are
gonna interact with and activities and
stuff it's the thought of it being
forever I hated like me uprooting her
and then wins the next kid moving in is
it gonna be five years before the next
kid moves in you know what if which kid
we don't like I can't talk for the
community but here in this case it's in
a circle of 1000 meters you have 36
other kids
so the riddle situation in in a
community is not automatically that you
you are going in the desert in Nevada
and Texas and anything and you are
really alone for two weeks and and you
you have to advertise it your kid all
the time it is a life outside of the
community if it's a good established
embedded in the society embedded
community there are interactions in for
any age possible in in the local area so
I I would not expect to go with my kid
to an abandoned place where I find
nobody else to play this is not social
and not healthy for kids but it's it was
more the question do you want to take
responsibility to be the first one to be
able to invite the second mother in all
these calls and you will have a lot of
calls in a short time this is more a
question of strategy than the high risk
and the other thing is if you really
start to travel with your kid and and
you find some communities and they
welcome you and they are not frightened
that you can't work 20 hours per week or
whatever then there are the kids also
around so it's maybe it's a question of
faith yeah yeah start all right we are
definitely way past the the our weekend
this is an interesting conversation and
it got a lot of this I find everything I
do hilarious cuz it never is what I
envisioned it it's always perfect are
you guys do you guys want to have one
again next week though and see what
comes out between now and then and see
and possibly I might invite more people
invite more people if you want as far as
bringing people on and having them have
that vision of what their community is
so they can let it go to it so they can
then be like oh what do you mean I'm
allowed to just go traveling around
Europe with my kid that's ridiculous
I would like to see this happen that we
have more thoughts like this and that
are more people able to join it even to
make it bigger to add more value and I
would see a reason in doing this because
even in this time after this pandemic
event there are many people searching
even many mothers
mothers with kids are searching for a
solution
and this channel and this your project
is is an option it's it's a kind of
online party and maybe you can identify
some people you want to meet in your
next holiday trip maybe you can invite
each other for for some time together
so it's an option yeah it's definitely
started a new wheels turning and so yes
I will do this for a next week it'll
probably be unzoom and then we can bring
as many people as we want we can break
off and figure out um more what we can
do during these conversations that it's
maybe not as free and open as I like it
to be more something like an idea cafe
or we are talking about a question and
breaking off into groups like how much
privacy do you need right like the kind
of questions that you would if you've
been an intentional community you know
where importance but how rigid are you
and then if you have a minute
intentional community getting little
sparks going but just having a touch
point to be able to break off into
groups and get to know each other get to
know what it looks like to even be in
this type of intentional community right
there just conversations okay so I will
make a new one for a next week one if
there was you'd said you didn't want to
mention a corporation or a company that
was helpful in finding these places in
Europe if you want to mention it in our
messenger group that would be great
you want to send us who would give you
some some links okay awesome
all right thanks one see you guys next
week